击向脑袋左边
Head caught to the left.
废其听力
Partial deafness in ear.
这是第一下
First point of attack.
第二 击向喉咙 废其声带 让他叫不出声
Two, throat. Paralyze the vocal cords, stop screaming.
第三 肯定是酒鬼 对准肝脏方向猛击肋骨
Three, got to be a heavy drinker. Punch the rib to the liver.
第四 也就是最后 拖住左腿 击碎膝盖骨
Four, finally, drag the left leg. Fist the patella.
小结 不省人事90秒
Summary prognosis Exactly 90 seconds
攻击效果 最多15分钟 完全康复 不太可能
Complete recovery of the colleges Unlikely.
- 帽子不错 - 我捡来的
- I like the hat. - I just picked it up.
你没带枪吗
You remember your revolver?
我就知道会忘带东西
I knew I'd forgotten something.
- 我以为家里炉子没关上 - 确实
- I thought I'd left the stove on. - You did.
应该够了吧
I think that's quite enough.
毕竟你是医生
You're a doctor, after all.
见到你一向很开心 华生
Always nice to see you, Watson.
警长呢
Where is the inspector?
在召集人马呢
He's getting his troops lined up.
那可不知道要等到什么时候了
That could be all day.
歇洛克·福尔摩斯
Sherlock Holmes.
还有他那条哈巴狗
And his loyal dog.
我很好奇 医生
Tell me, doctor
作为一名医务工作者 你是否 喜欢过我的杰作
As a medical man, have you enjoyed my work?
让你看看 我有多喜欢
Let me show you how much I've enjoyed it.
华生 不
Watson! Don't!
仔细观察
Observe.
你怎么看到的
How did you see that?
因为这就是我在找的
Because I was looking for it.
布莱克伍德
Lord Blackwood!
你好像有点吃惊啊
You seem surprised.
我想说我们更应该关心那姑娘
I would say that the girl deserves our attention more than he.
确实
Indeed.
哦 我要是你的话就不会去碰
Oh, I'd leave that alone if I were you, boyo.
好孩子
Good lad.
来的真是时候 雷斯垂德
Impeccable timing, Lestrade.
一个进医院 一个送刑场
We've one for the doctor, and one for the rope.
- 克拉基 - 长官
- Clarky? - Sir.
这位女士要马上送医院
This woman needs a hospital immediately.
- 把她抬到圣母像后面 - 这边 对
- Put her in the back of the maraya. - Right lads, that's it.
不介意吧
If you don't mind.
别让我看见他
Get him out of my sights.
你应该等我发指令的
And you were supposed to wait for my orders.
要是我等的话 你就要来收尸
If I had, you'd be clearing up a corpse.
捕风捉影了
and chasing a rumor.
况且雇我的是这姑娘的父母 不是苏格兰场
Besides, the girl's parents hired me, not the Yard.
为什么要请我这个外人帮你 我也不清楚
Why they thought you'd require any assistance is beyond me?
- 伦敦城总算能松口气了 - 确实
- Well, London will breathe a sigh of relief. - Indeed.
- 恭喜你 雷斯垂德 - 太棒了 督察
- Congratulations, Lestrade. - Bravo, Inspector.
来根雪茄吧
Have a cigar.
先生们
Gentlemen...
笑一个
Cheese!
《大侦探福尔摩斯》
156比80
156 over 80.
很好
Very good.
我的神经这几年已经 好得不能再好了 谢谢
Me nerves have been the best in years, thanks to you.
哦 跟我说说
Oh, tell me something:
你的新住所 你什么时候搬
Your new premises, when you moving in?
应该一周内就搬
I should be moving within the week.
卡文迪许区
Cavendish Place.
那里女人不少哦
And there will be a womens touch too.
- 太好了 - 确实啊
- That's marvelous. - Indeed.
老天爷
Good god!
- 有人开枪 - 不 不 不 不
- This was gunfire! - No, no, no, no.
是用锤子砸钉子吧
Hammer and nail, wasn't it?
是我同事 应该是在挂画
My colleagues, probably just... putting up a painting.
我去看看
I'll go and check.
- 你同事 - 对
- Your colleague? - Yes
他不会跟你一起搬走吧
He wont be moving with you, will he?
不 他不搬
No, he wont.
哈德森太太
Mrs. Hudson...
我可不想自己进去 尤其他手上还拿着枪
I wont go in there by myself. No one has got a gun in this house.
你不用进去 把报纸给我吧
You will not need to go in there at all. Give me the paper.
你走了我该怎么办 医生
What will I do when you leave, Doctor?
他会把整间屋子都拆掉的
He'll have the whole house down!
他没案子破而已
He just needs another case, that's all.
你能不能再晚点结婚
Couldn't you have a longer engagement?
有火药味 太不象话了 这可是在家里
I smell gunpowder. It's not right you know! Not in a domestic environment.
谢谢 菲利普队长
Thank you, Captain Phillip.
喝点茶压压惊吧
Perhaps a nice cup of tea...
下周老时间见
Same time next week.
来 队长 楼下要安静些
Come on, Captain. It's quieter downstairs.
哈德森太太 给他来点东西提提神
Mrs. Hudson? Bring something to cheer him up.
请求进入军火库
Permission to enter the armoury.
准
Granted.
华生 我在设计一个
Watson, I am in the process of inventing a device
能减小枪声的装置
that depresses the sound of a gunshot.
显然你没成功
It's not working.
哦 我能看看吗
Oh, may I see that?
自从上一个案子以来 你有3个月没接案子了吧
You know it's been three months, since your last case?
悠着点 悠着点 华生 别这么狠
Gently. Gently, Watson. Be gentle with me.
你不觉得你应该再找件案子来查吗
Don't you think it's time you found another one.
找不到 但 我同意
I can't but, agree.
我的脑子受不了这种无所事事的状态 我需要难题 需要工作
My mind rebels techniques give me problems, give me work.
越快越好
The sooner the better.
- 报纸 - 谢谢
- Paper. - Thank you.
看看 还有封信
Let's see then. There's a letter here.
是 皇家园林的
From...
拉姆塞太太寄来的
Mrs. Ramsey, of Queenspark.
她丈夫失踪了
Her husband's disappeared.
在比利时呢 还有他的女帮厨
He's in Belgium, with the scurry maid.
已经11月了
Is it November?
对 福尔摩斯
Yes, Holmes. Alright.
好吧 雷德福夫人
Lady Rathford reports...
给她的祖母绿项链报了失
her emerald bracelet has disappeared.
保险诈骗
An insurance swindle.
雷德福勋爵的马跑得不快 女人倒是换得很勤
Lord Rathford like's fast women and slow ponies.
等布莱克伍德吊死后 你负责验尸吧
I see you're the attending physician, at Blacwood's hanging.
对
Yes
那是我们最后一次合作的案子
It was our last case together
我希望能看到案子最终结束
and I wanted to see it through to the end.
还有一个路易斯先生
A Mr. Louis...
我此刻只关心一个案子
There's only one case, that intrigues me at present.
哈德森太太奇案
The Curious Case of Mrs. Hudson
总是不在的女房东
The absent tea landlady.
我一直在观察她的进进出出
I've been studying her comings and goings
- 实在太诡异了 - 茶水 福尔摩斯先生
- and they appear most... sinister. - Tea, Mr. Holmes?
下毒了吗 “奶妈”
Is it poisoned, "Nanny"?
你已经够毒的了
There's enough of that in you already.
别碰 我的东西都摆得很好
Don't touch. Everything is in it's proper place.
就跟平时一样 “奶妈”
As per usual, "Nanny".
哦 他又把狗弄死了
Oh, his killed the dog... again.
你又对格莱斯顿做什么了
What have you done to, Gladston now?
我只是测试了下新型麻醉药而已
I was simply testing a new anesthetic.
它并不介意
He doesn't mind.
福尔摩斯
Holmes
作为你的医生
as your doctor...
它很快就会好起来的
He'll be good in no time.
我以一个朋友的身份
As your friend...
你已经在这间屋子待了两星期了 我坚持要你出去走走
You've been in this room for two weeks. I insist, you have to get out.
外面的世界都我来说没什么意思
There's nothing of interest, for me, out there on Earth.
- 那 你今晚有空吗 - 当然
- So, you're free this evening? - Absolutely.
- 一起吃晚饭 - 很好
- Dinner? - Wonderfull.
- 皇家餐厅 - 我最喜欢了
- The Royal? - My favourite.
玛丽会来
Mary's coming.
- 我没空 - 我要你见见她 福尔摩斯
- It's not fair. - You're meeting her, Holmes!
你求婚了吗
Have you proposed yet?
还没 我还没找到合适的戒指
No, I haven't found the right ring.
哦 那就还不算正式
Oh, then it's not official.
这已经是板上钉钉了 不管你赞成与否
It's happening, whether you like it or not.
晚上8点半 皇家餐厅
20:30, the Royal.
- 穿好点 - 你穿好点吧
- Where a jacket. - You wear a jacket.
福尔摩斯
Holmes!
你来早了
You're early.
流行嘛
Fashionably.
玛丽·摩斯坦小姐
Miss Mary Morsten.
老天啊 很荣幸
Oh my goodness. What a pleasure.
我真不知道他干嘛要 拖这么久才介绍我们认识
For the life of me, I don't know why it's taken him so long to introduce us properly.
是我荣幸才对
The pleasure is mine.
见到你 我激动万分 福尔摩斯先生
It really is quite a thrill meeting you, Mr. Holmes.
我听说了很多你的事迹
I've heard so much about you.
我家有一大堆侦探小说 柯林斯的 爱伦·坡的
I have a pile of detective novels at home... Collins, Poe.
没错
It's true.
只是觉得有时候
It can seem a little
通过细枝末节作出惊人推断 有点牵强
far fetched though, at times. Making these grand assumptions out of tiny details.
也不尽然吧
That's not quite right is it?
事实上 细枝末节倒是最重要的
In fact, the little details are by far, the most important.
- 就拿华生来说 - 我也这么想的
- Take Watson... - I intend to.
你看他这根手杖 是用稀有的非洲蛇木制成的
You see this walking stick, a rare African snake wood.
藏着把高强钢打造的利刃
Hiding a blade.
阿富汗战争时没几个 老兵才能获得的奖励
Few were rewarded to the veterans of the afgan war,
所以我推断 他曾是名得过勋章的军人
so I can assume, he's a decorated soldier.
坚强 勇敢 天生的冒险家
Strong, brave, born to be an adventurer.
又很干练 跟所有军人一样
and neat, like all military men.
再看看他的口袋
Now, I check his pockets.
啊 一张拳击赛的票
Ah, a stamp from a boxing match.
如此说来 他又有点好赌
Now, I can assume he's a bit of a gambler.
我要是你 就得看好嫁妆
I'd keep an eye on that dowry, if I were you.
- 那是陈年旧事了 - 对 都过去了
- Those days are behind me. - Right, behind you.
好几次把我们的房租都赔进去了
It's cost us the rent, more than once.
福尔摩斯先生 你跟约翰本来就很熟
Well with all due respect, Mr. Holmes, You know John very well.
如果是一个完全不认识的陌生人呢
What about a complete stranger?
你能从我身上看出什么
What can you tell about me?
- 你? - 我觉得这有点不
- You? - I don't think that's...
- 我不知道是不是 - 吃饭的时候就算了
- I don't know if that's... - Not at dinner.
- 要不下次吧 - 我坚持要这次说
- Perhaps another time. - I insist.
- 你坚持 - 我们讨论过这个
- You insist? - You remember tht we discussed this.
是女士坚持的
The lady insists
- 你是名家庭教师 - 很好
- You're a governess. - Well done.
对 很好 要不要 服务生
Yes, well done. Shall we... Waiter!
你的学生 是个8岁的男孩
Your student... It's a boy of eight.
其实查理是7岁
Charlie is seven, actually.
在他这个年龄算是高个子 他今天对你弹墨水了
So he's tall for his age. He flicked you with ink today.
- 我脸上沾到墨水了 - 你的脸没什么不妥
- Is there ink on my face? - There is nothing wrong with your face.
是你的耳朵上有两滴
There are two drops on your ear infact.
印度蓝几乎没法洗掉
India blue is near impossible to wash off.
反正那孩子有点毛躁
Anyway, rather impetuous of that boy,
但作为一名经验丰富的教师 你并没有反应过激
but you're to experienced to react rashly, which is why
所以那家女主人才会把这副项链借给你
the lady for whom you work lent you that necklace.
珍珠 钻石 毫无瑕疵的红宝石
Pearls, diamonds, flawless rubies.
不像是家庭女教师穿戴的珠宝
Hardly the gems of a governess .
然而你没戴的首饰反倒透露出更多
However, the jewls you are not wearing, tell us rather more.
- 福尔摩斯 - 你订过婚
- Holmes! - You were engaged.
戒指不见了 稍浅的肤色说明
The ring has gone, but the lighter skin suggests
你曾经戴着戒指在国外待过一段时间
that you spent some time abroard proudly
但又随后认识到它 并不怎么高的真实价值
that is until you were informed that it's true
于是你毁掉婚约回到英格兰
and then you broke of the engagement and returned to, England
或许是为一个更好的前途 比如说嫁给一名医生
for better prospects. A doctor perhaps?
你说的都没错 福尔摩斯先生 但除了一点
You're right on all accounts Mr. Holmes, apart from one.
我并没有抛弃他
I didn't leave him.
他去世了
He died.
很好 老伙计
Well done, old boy.
起来打啊
Get up and fight!
来啊
Come on!
好了 大块头 结束了
That's it. We're done.
你赢了 恭喜
You won. Congratulations.
喂 我们还没打完呢
Oy, we aint done yet.
这时候不能丧失理智
This must not register on an emotional level.
首先 扰乱对手的视线
First, distract target.
接着挡住他这时候打来的刺拳
Then block his blind jab.
回一记侧拳 击向对方左脸
Counter with cross to the left cheek.
用双风贯耳扰乱对方
Discombobulate.
他会头晕目眩 胡乱打出一击 这时用肘部抵挡
Dazed, he'll attempt a wild hit. employ the elbow block.
然后猛击对方身体
And body shot.
接下来挡住左边的进攻
block next left.
肘击右下巴
weaken right jaw.
造成骨折
Now fracture.
破坏右肋
Break right ribs.
造成腹腔神经丛创伤
Traumamatize, solar plexus.
将下巴完全打脱臼
dislocate jaw entirely.
朝横隔膜猛踹
Kick in the diaphragm.
结果如下
In summary:
下巴骨折 肋骨3根骨裂 4根断裂
Jaw fractured, three ribs cracked four broken,
横隔膜内出血
diaphragm haemorrhaging.
生理恢复 6星期
Physical recovery: 6 weeks.
心理恢复 6个月
For psychological recovery: 6 months.
向我后脑勺吐口水的能力
Capacity to spit tobacco:
完全丧失
Neutralized.
这是哪一出
Where did that come from?
该死的到底是怎么回事 查理
What the hell's going on here, Charley?
布莱克伍德像是给他施了咒
Lord Blackwood's put him on some kind of spell, sir.
好像他体内有东西要往外烧
It's like he's burning from the inside out!
闭嘴
Shut up!
查理 查理
Charley. Charley!
马上把这人抬去医务室
Take this man to the infirmary! Now!
这是怎么回事 布莱克伍德
What's this all about then, Blackwood?
我要见个人
There's someone I want to see.
- 华生 - 对
- Watson? - Right.
我们走
Let's go.
这一开始仅仅是个实验
What started as a mere experiment
如今却带来了一个极具意义的发现
has brought me to the threshold of monumental discovery
如果我弹半音音阶
Now if I play, chromatic scale
毫无反应
there's no measurable response.
要知道 你喝的东西是用来做眼部手术的
You do know, what you're drinking is meant for eye surgery.
但是
But... now,
这就非常了不起了
and this is remarkable
如果我调到八音簇
if I change to eight tone clusters
瞧
Voila!
它们便会沿逆时针方向
They fly in counter-clockwise,
以同心圆的方式飞舞
synchronized in circles.
华生 这太不寻常了
Watson this is exceptional.
我 运用音乐理论 化无序为有序
I, using musical theory, have created order out from chaos.
你是怎么把它们引进去的
How did you lure them in?
好问题
Excellent question.
一个个地引进去的 我已经弄了有6小时了
Individually, I've been at it for six hours.
要是我这样呢
And what happens if I do this?
把自己弄干净些
Clean yourself up.
布莱克伍德的遗愿是要见你
You are Blackwood's last request.
看看那些塔形结构
Look at those towering structures.
这是吊桥从未尝试过的组合
It's the first combination of a suspension bridge ever attempted.
非常有创意
Most innovative.
我们帝国真是勤劳勇敢
What an industrious empire!
哦 我昨晚替你赢了比赛
Oh, I have your winnings from last night.
你没在 我照你的习惯替你下了注
You weren't there, so I made your customery bet.
你是对的 我会把这个 和你的支票簿放一起的
You're right. I'll keep it with your checkbook,
安全地锁在我的抽屉里
locked safely away in my draw.
你知道有家歌剧院在演“唐·璜”吗
Did you know the opera house is featuring "Don Giovanni"?
我很容易就能弄两张票
I could easily procure a couple of tickets
要是今晚你有兴致的话
If you had any cultural inclinations this evening.
安静是你很大的优点
You have a grand gift of silence,
华生 作为同伴来说这是相当难得的
Watson, it makes you quite invaluable as a companion.
我知道她订过婚
I knew she'd been engaged.
她告诉过我
She told me.
看来是不去看戏了
So that's, no to the opera then.
那是我的马甲
That was my waistcoat.
我想我们都认为这太小了
I thought we agreed it's too small for you.
- 我要你放手 - 我想我们意见一致
- I'd like it back. - I thought we agreed.
给我放手
I want it back.
这边请 福尔摩斯先生
This way, Mr. Holmes.
布莱克伍德似乎让民众异常狂热啊
Blackwood seems to have got the crowd into some what of a fear frenzy.
我想等到他翘辫子 狂热的人会更多
I'm sure it will disperse once his feet stop twitching.
要一起来吗
Care to come along?
不了 你自己去吧 老兄
No, you're on your own, old cock.
他活着的时候就没我什么事
I have no business with him whilst he's alive.
随你的便 “小弟弟”
Suit yourself, "mother hen".
好像这里还有不少空位啊
It seems you still have lots of rooms to let.
我们也是不得已挪开犯人的 先生
We had to move the prisoners, sir.
否则他们就会闹事
Otherwise we're gonna have a riot on our hands.
他会对囚犯施妖术
He has a peculiar effect on the inmates.
就好像他能进入他们思想一样
As though, he can get inside their heads.
要是你有其它事的话 我想自己能过去
I'm sure I can find my own way if you have other duties to perform.
非常感谢 先生 谢谢
Much obliged, sir. Thank you.
我立于海边沙滩之上 看见海水中出现一头怪兽
... and the dragon of the sea. And I saw the beast out of bodies of water
长有十角七头 角上又戴有十个冠冕
... had ten horns and seven heads, with ten crowns on his horns,
每个头上都有个亵渎神灵的名号
and each head had a blasphemous name.
他们崇拜给予这怪兽力量的古龙
And people have glorified ... dragon which he gave the beast
又崇拜这怪兽 说
to e are glorified and the beast, saying,
谁又跟这兽一样
"What is like the beast?"
这兽长着豹身
Beast which I saw has the body of a leopard,
熊掌及狮口
but had feet of a bear and was the lion's mouth.
古龙赐于这兽力量 王位及权威...
The dragon gave power unto the beast, his throne and great authority ...
我喜欢你搞的内饰装修
I love what you done to the place.
很高兴你接受了我的邀请
So glad you can accept my invitation.
我只是有点担心
I just have a small point of concern.
有什么能帮忙的吗
How can I help?
因为感兴趣 我跟进了这系列谋杀
I've already followed the murders with some intrest...
虽然我最初是因为 被害人的家人才接的这案子
and although my heart went out primarily to the families of the victims.
但我还是无法忽视
I couldn't but notice a criminal mastery.
在背后操控一切的你
And the stroke of your brush.
你太客气了
You're too kind.
但是相较而言 你的密文绘画
However, by comparison, your work in the crypt
更像是指画
looks more like a finger painting.
所以你很好奇是不是 还有什么更大的阴谋
So now you're curious if there's a larger game afoot?
或者说 呃
Either that or, um...
很快 我朋友要宣布你的死讯
shortly my friend, you'll be pronounced dead
我只是陪着他而已
and I thought I might keep him company.
你错就错在以为
Your mistake is to imagine that anything
世俗的一切导致如今这一切
that is earthly has led us to this moment.
你错误的判断在于假设我是主使人
Your error of judgment is to assume that I'm holding the brush.
我只是个引路人而已
I'm merely a channel.
我只希望早点抓住你
My only wish is that I could have caught you sooner.
我就不会那5个人枉送性命了
You see? Five lives might have been spared.
那些人的死是必须的
Those lives were a necessity.
必要的牺牲
Sacrifice.
还有5条微不足道的性命 将为一个更宏伟的目标做出贡献
Five other wise meaningless creatures called to serve a greater purpose.
我在想他们会不会同意华生和我解剖你的大脑
I wonder if they'll let me and Watson dissect your brain.
当然了 要等他们先吊死你
After you hang, of course.
我敢打赌 你脑子里的异变 肯定具有重大科学意义
I'd wager, there is some deformity that would be scientifically significant.
而你也能为一个更宏伟的目标做出贡献
Then you too, could serve a greater purpose.
福尔摩斯 眼睛睁睁大
Holmes, you must widen your gaze.
我担心你低估了接下来要发生的事
I'm concerned, you underestimate the gravity of coming events.
你我注定要开始一段 能改变整个自然结构的历程
You and I are bound together on a journey that would twist the very fabric of nature.
但在你那充满逻辑的外表下 我嗅到了一丝软弱
But beneath your mask of logic I sense a frailty...
这让我很担心
That worries me.
坚强起来 福尔摩斯
Steal your mind, Holmes.
我需要你
I need you.
你从上议院成员变作阶下囚
I'd say, you've come a long way down from a house of Lords.
- 我会东山再起 - “一路顺风”
- I will rise again. - "Bon voyage".
注意听着
Pay attention!
还会再死3个 你做什么都救不了他们
Three more will die and there is nothing you can do to save them.
你控制不了局势 认命吧
You must accept that this is beyond your control.
等你意识到是你让一切成为可能
By the time you realise you made all of this possible
你将彻底发狂
it will be the last sane thought in your head.
他想怎样
What did he want?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
但我觉得你们不用跟来 至少这个不用
But I don't think you need to follow. Not this one.
亨利·布莱克伍德 你因施展邪术
Lord Henry Blackwood, you are sentenced to death
杀害五名无辜年轻女子
for the practice of black magic
杀害第六名未遂
the unholy murder of five innocent young women
被判处死刑
and an attempted murder of a sixth.
你有何遗言吗
Do you have any final words?
死亡 仅仅是开始
Death... is only the beginning.
布莱克伍德已确认死亡
That is the end of Lord Blackwood.
伦敦一年的这几天真是阴冷
London's so bleak this time of year.
并不是我在想新泽西的家
Not that I'm pining for New Jersey,
我只是更希望在冬天外出
but much prefer to travel in winter.
我给你从叙利亚带了点东西
Here, I bought you these. All the way from Syria.
我从约旦带了些精致的枣子
I found these exquisite dates in Jordan.
还有你最喜欢的
and your favorite...
基克拉迪群岛的橄榄
Olives from the Cyclades.
我想我们或许能一起开个茶会
I thought we might have a little tea party.
摆桌子的时候我发现了这个
and while I was setting the table, I found this.
一份标有我名字的文件
A file with my name on it.
西班牙国王的韦拉斯克斯画像遭窃
"The theft of the Velasquez portrait King of Spain.
海军文档失窃 保加利亚首相引咎辞职
Missing naval documents lead to resignation of Bulgarian prime minister
由于桃色绯闻
scandalous affair ends engagement of... "
哈普斯堡王子 与罗曼诺夫公主的婚约取消
"Prince Romanov. "of Austria and Princess.
我只是在研究你的手法
I'm simply studying your methods.
如果当局要我抓捕你的话
Should the authorities ask me to hunt you down.
但我没看见文章里有提到我的名字啊
But I don't see my name in any of these articles.
但很明显是你的手法
But your signature was clear.
这是印度王公丢失的钻石吗
Is that the Maharaja's missing diamond?
还是只是个纪念品
Or just another souvenir?
别总抓着过去不放
Let's not dwell on the past.
好吗
Shall we?
看起来你现在没案子可办
Now, by the looks of things, I'd say you were between jobs.
你现在也是没夫君可侍
And you between husbands.
结婚后你得到多少
How much did you get for the ring?
他又无聊又爱吃醋 睡觉还打呼
He was boring and jealous and he snored.
我又变回艾琳·艾德勒了
I'm Irene Adler, again.
谢谢
Thank you.
我要你帮个忙
I need your help.
帮忙找个人
I need you to find someone.
你老是这么多疑干嘛
Why are you always so suspicious.
你要我按照事件的时间顺序 还是首字母顺序回答你
Should I answer chronologically or alphabetically?
小心点 别被锋利的信封割伤了
Careful not to cut yourself on this lethal envelope.
你要知道的一切都在信封里
I think you'll find all the information inside.
你为谁工作
Who are you working for?
看来我得自己查出来
So I'll have to find out the hard way.
把钱收好吧 我没说我会接这案子
Keep your money, I didn't say I'll take the case.
就当这是我赌你会接的吧
Consider it a wager that you will.
还记得大饭店吗
You remember the Grandl?
我还住我们以前那间房
They gave me our old room.
帮我抵着门 谢谢 医生
Hold the door. Thank's, doctor.
女士
Ma'am.
- 他会接的 - 干得好 艾德勒小姐
- He'll do it. - Well done, Miss Adler.
正因为这样我才会请你
That's precisely why I hired you.
我打赌他会在24小时内把人找到
I'll wager, he'll have our man in the next 24 hours.
最好如此
He'd better.
布莱克伍德的所作所为缺不了李奥丹
Reordan is the key to what Blackwood was doing.
他对我的计划也至关重要
He's essential to my plan.
见鬼 你在干嘛 走路不长眼
Damn! What are you doing? Can't you see where you're going?
给我滚开
Get of my way!
带我一程吧 先生 我走了很远的路
A little ride, I've come along way, sir.
脚上都有老茧了
.
上帝拯救女王
God save the queen!
上帝拯救女王 先生
God save the Queen, sir.
还不快滚
Get off out of it!
瞧瞧你
Look at you?
为何你唯一关心的女人
Why is the only woman you've ever cared about
是个江洋大盗
a world class criminal?
你是受虐狂
Are you a masochist?
容我解释
Allow me to explain...
我来吧
Allow me!
她是唯一胜过你的敌手 还不止一次
She's the only adversary, who ever out smarted you. Twice.
好一个大傻冒
Made a proper idiot out of you.
得 你乐呵吧
Right, you've had your fun.
- 话说回来 她要什么 - 现在得坚持住
- What she after, anyway? - It's time to press on.
她会要什么呢
What could she possibly need?
无关紧要
It doesn't matter.
不在场证明 胡须 还是人肉小船
An alibi, a beard. A human canoe.
她倒是有这个本事 骑着你沿泰晤士河逆流而上
She can sit on your back and paddle you up the Thames.
华生 这与你无关 不是吗
That's no consequence to you really, is it Watson?
我们一起的最后一个案子已经结了
We've done our, last case together.
我已经看过了
I've already read it.
寻人
Missing person.
路克·雷欧登
Luke Reordan.
1米47 红棕色头发 没有门牙 案子结了
4 foot 10, red hair, no front teeth. Case solved.
她显然不锺意你这一型的
You're obviously not her type.
她喜欢姜黄色头发的小个子
She likes gingered dwarfs.
那叫侏儒
Midgets.
- 这么说你认可了 - 我不同意
- So, you agree. - No, I don't agree.
你要知道 那不只是个术语
It's more than a technicality, you see.
你把矮人的种类搞混了
You are misrepresenting the dimensions of short peoples.
我知道我多嘴招你厌了
I've said too much. I can tell, I've upset you.
没有 我只是想说 那个人...
No, I'm just simply stating, that one has...
你刚才在干嘛
What were you doing?
- 让我解释吗 - 我倒是想听听
- Will you allow me to explain? - I wish you would.
- 福尔摩斯 你在干嘛 - 没干嘛
- Holmes? What are you doing? - Nothing.
- 你是不是戴了 - 假鼻子 没啊
- Are you wearing a... - A false nose? No.
那个不是
Tell me, that was...
福尔摩斯 你在干嘛
Holmes! Where are you going?
华生
Watson?
华生 救命
Help! Watson!
小甜甜 为你准备了些花儿
Got some flowers for you, sweetheart.
你这么漂亮 算你便宜点
Cut you a deal, cos you're so pretty.
噢 真走运
Oh, my lucky day!
美人儿 有东西给我吗
Hello gorgeous, you got something for me.
别动
Don't move!
瞧这儿是什么
Now, what have we got here?
多谢
Thank you.
那才是我认识的艾琳
That's the Irene I know.
华生 我对这个男人很好奇 他把艾琳整得服服贴贴的
This man Intrigues me, Watson, His got her on the edge.
她可不是吃素的
And she's no mean feet.
她感到威胁 很怕他
She's intimidated, she's scared of him.
但她还是为他卖命
Yet she work's for him.
没错
Right.
虽然不关我事 不过我还是 建议你别插手这个案子
It is nothing to do with me, but I advise you to leave the case alone.
我现在有的选吗
I may not always have a choice.
毕竟我有钱自己付房租了 多亏有你
After all, I may be paying the rent on my own soon. Thanks to you.
把那玩意儿从我脸上拿开
Get that out of my face.
又不在“你脸上” 在我手里呢
It's not "in your face" it's in my hand.
不管你手里是啥 给我拿开
Get whatever's in your hand out of my face.
- 福尔摩斯先生 - 克拉基
- Mr. Holmes! - Clarky!
打扰了 雷斯垂德警长让您 立刻跟我走一趟
Sorry. Inspector Lestrade asks you come with me at once.
这回又怎么了 忘了回苏格兰场的路了
What's he done now, lost his way to Scotland Yard?
华生 就给他个指南针吧 他需要我们呢
Watson drop a compass, he needs us.
不关我事
No, you means you.
先生 是布莱克伍德 他
It's Lord Blackwood, sir. He...
他好像又复活了 先生
Well... it appears he's come back from the grave, sir.
- 真有趣 - 多机灵
- Most engaging. - Very clever.
我宣布了他的死亡
I pronounced the man dead myself.
有什么证据
What are the facts?
墓地管理员说他今天早上 亲眼看见他从墓地里走出去了
Groundkeeper, claims he saw him walking through the graveyard just this morning, sir.
这件事就交给你了
I'll leave this in your capable hands.
我和玛丽有约
I have an appointment with, Mary.
又不是我要名声扫地了
It's not my reputation at stake here.
别来这套
Don't try that.
- 报纸有没有走漏风声 - 我们会尽量收紧口风的 先生
- Has the newspaper got wind of it yet. - Well that's what we're trying to avoid, sir.
毫无疑问
Certainly.
- 现在情况如何 - 恐慌 惊恐万分 先生
- What's the major concern? - Panic. Sheer bloody panic, sir.
那是自然
Indeed.
福尔摩斯 你不会当真了吧
You're not taking this seriously, Holmes?
没错 你也该如此
Yes, as you should.
这可是职业操守的问题
It's a matter of professional integrity.
有哪个女孩想嫁给一个
No girl wants to marry a doctor
是生是死都分不清的医生
who can't tell If a man's dead or not.
克拉基 你觉得哪个队赢了
Who do you think won the match, Clarky?
- 什么 - 球赛呀
- Sir? - The rugby match.
你们可是把现场破坏殆尽啊
Your boys have done a magnificent job of obliterating any potential evidence.
确实 不过至少他们不会错过...
Yes, but atleats they never miss an opportunity...
错失良机的机会
to miss an opportunity.
福尔摩斯 你请自便
You took your time, Holmes.
在第三天
And on the third day...
这些板都是砂岩做的 每个都重达半吨
These slabs are sand stone, they half a ton each
从里头被砸碎了
and they were smashed open from the inside .
雷斯垂德 那棺材呢
Lestrade. What of the coffin?
我们正要把它弄上来
We are in the process of bringing it up now.
听着
Listen...
唔 对了
Hmm... Right.
正要弄上来 还是在考虑要弄上来
At what stage of the process? Contemplative?
我们的证人呢
And how is our witness?
在那儿
He's over there.
显然他非常紧 紧 紧
And apparently he's got ca... ca... ca...
紧张 先生
Catatonic, sir.
- 他有点神志不清 - 好的
- He's not feeling very well. - Yes
要是你们再这么哆嗦 就等着给我加班吧
If you lot don't stop behaving like a bunch of quivering milk maids, you're on double time.
快给我下去把棺材弄上来
Now you get down there, and you bring that coffin up, now!
今天还好吗 先生
Good day, sir!
没什么
It's alright.
我是医生
I'm a doctor.
他紧张得要命
The man's in shock.
- 让他再缓缓 - 证人声称
- He may need a few moments - The witness states that
他看见布莱克伍德从坟墓里爬了出来
he saw, lord Blackwood, rise from the grave.
- 如何 - 什么
- Well? - Well?
你宣布他已死
You pronounced him dead.
他没有脉搏啊
He had no pulse.
我的天
Good lord.
不是布莱克伍德
That's not Blackwood.
这下证据确凿无疑
Well, now we have a firm grasp, of the obvious.
死亡时间
Time of death?
大约两公分
2 thirds of an inch
这么推算死亡时间 应该是在10至12小时之前
which would put the time of death at between 10-12 hours ago.
能借你笔一用吗
May I borrow your pen?
- 没有门牙的矮人 - 侏儒
- Headless dwarf. - Midget.
我知道我看见了什么
I know what I saw!
那是布莱克伍德
It was Blackwood!
就像看见你们一样
As clear as I see you.
当死者复生
And when the dead walk...
生者将为之殉葬
the living will fill these coffins.
那好
Well...
好 把盖子合上 现场整理干净
Right, put the lid on and clean this up.
你真的相信他复活了
You really believe he was resurrected?
问题是“怎么”复活的 游戏开始了
The question is not "if" but "how." The games afoot.
一鼓作气往前直冲吧 一边冲 一边喊
Follow your spirit and upon this charge cried
上帝保佑亨利 英格兰和圣乔治
god for Harry, England and St. George.
给 为什么非得是那家鱼和炸薯条店呢
Here you are. Why that certain fish and chips store
- 我不明白 - 因为他们使用了一种特殊的啤酒
- I don't understand - Well there's a particular pier
确切的说 是北方的烈性黑啤酒
they use out in the back, northern stout, to be exact.
你要知道 福尔摩斯
You know, Holmes
我在战时见过一些无法理解的事
I've seen things in war I don't understand.
在印度 我曾经照面过一个 预言自己怎么死的人
In India, I once met a man who predicted his own death
子弹的数量和射中的位置 都精准无误
right down to the number and placement of the bullets that killed him.
福尔摩斯 你得承认
You have to admit, Holmes
在理论上 超自然因素 是可以解释这起案子的
that a supernatural explanation to this case, is theoretically possible.
同意
Agreed.
不过 没有证据的推理 可是会大错特错的
But, it is a huge mistake to theorize before one has data.
人不可避免地会扭曲事实否定理论 而不是依据理论来判定事实
Inevitably, one begins to twist facts to shoot theories, instead of theories to shoot facts
所以我相信
That said I believe
这个侏儒是关键
our midget is the key to this.
手表上弦的孔洞周围有抓痕
Right. Scratches around the key hole where the watch is wound.
你得出什么结论
What does that tell you?
这人多半是醉了
The man was most likely a drunk.
每次上弦 手滑了 所以有了抓痕
Every time he wound the watch, his hand slipped, hence the scratches.
非常好 华生
Yes Very good, Watson.
你的推理能力已经相当了得
You have developed considerable deductive powers of your own.
再来看看 有几个姓名缩写
Let's see now. There are several sets of initials.
- 皮条客的记号 - 真棒
- Porn brokers marks. - Excellent.
最近的一个是M.H. M.H. M.H.
Most recent of which are: "M.H. M.H. M.H...
- M.H.是指 - Maddison和Haig
- M.H is for... - "Maddison and Haig.
他们可以告诉我们地址
They should be able to give us an address.
真巧
What a coincidence.
有件事你忘了推理 福尔摩斯
There's one thing you failed to deduce from the watch, Holmes.
我不觉得
I think not.
表上的时间
The time.
我得回去了
I have to get back, Holmes.
和亲家喝个茶
Taking tea with the in-laws..
- 先生 我能给你看相吗 - 不行
- Can I predict your future, sir? - Absolutely not.
不用 谢了 女士
No thank you, ma'am.
你得听我说说
You need to hear what I have to tell you.
吉普赛女郎 我们不需要
We have no need of your lucky heather Gypsy women.
就算是和玛丽有关
Even if it's to do with Mary.
我看见两个男人
I see two men.
两兄弟 没有血缘关系 不过关系很铁
Brothers. Not in blood, but in boned.
玛丽呢
What of Mary?
M代表玛丽 指婚姻 噢 你们会结婚的
M for Mary, for marriage. Oh, you will be married.
继续
Go on.
我看见各式图案的桌布 还有瓷做的雕塑
I see patterned table cloths and china figurines.
和蕾丝桌巾
and lace doilies...
桌巾
doilies...
蕾丝
Lace doilies...
桌巾 福尔摩斯
doilies... Holmes.
- 你这人竟无耻到这个地步了 - 不关我的事
- Does your depravity know, no bounds? - No.
她发胖了 还长胡子
Oh she turns fat and has a beard...
皮疣呢
And what of the warts?
- 满身皮疣 - 够了 够了
- She is covered in warts... - Enough, enough.
- 有很多吗? - 可以了 够了
- Are they extensive? - Please, enough!
这是芙劳若多年来最准的预言了
It's the most apt prediction, Flora's made in ages.
也正因如此 你找不到一枚合适的戒指
And precisely the reason you can't find a suitable ring.
我的钱在你身上吗
Do you have my money?
你害怕悲剧的生活
You are terrified of a life without the thrill of a macabre.
我那份在身上吗
Do you have my cut?
- 承认吧 承认吧 - 把钱给我
- Admit it, admit it! - Give me my money!
福尔摩斯
Holmes.
噢 了解
Oh I see.
谢了
Thank you.
这下可好 你买了戒指 我有了那侏儒的地址
Well you've got your ring, and I've got the address for my ginger midget.
应该就在前面
Should be just there.
我觉得她定会喜欢的
I think she'll really like this.
我还有富余
And I have some change in my pocket.
- 要我替你看着吗 - 不用
- Should I look after it for you? - No, no.
- 别在这儿赌输了 - 不会
- Don't give it away here. - No!
我要去见玛丽了
I have to go see Mary.
替我问候她
Give them my best.
还有她的家人
And the family as well.
有个完全信得过的人在身边
It does make a considerable difference to me, having someone with me
确实不一样啊
on whom I can throughly rely.
我只能留给你十分钟
Well, you can rely on me for exactly 10 minutes.
他清楚有人会来找他
He clearly fely something was coming to get him.
已经来过了
Or something did.
是艾琳
Irene was here,
要么就是那侏儒和她用同一款巴黎香水
either that or the ginger midget wore the same Parisian perfume.
啊 腐败味
Ah, putrefaction.
硫氨酸 还混杂着其它气味
Ammonium sulphate, among other aromas.
磷
Phosphorus.
甲醛
Formaldehyde.
看来他是打算把巫术
It looks like he was attempting to combine
和化学方程式结合起来
some kind of sorcery and scientific formula.
更重要的是
More importantly...
他打算处理掉的东西
What he was trying to dispose of.
钾和镁
Potassium and magnesium.
硫酸
sulfuric acid.
只要没烧完 墨迹里头就有铁
Why the iron went out of the ink as long as it's not to burnt
真特别
Peculiar.
水合杜鹃花
Hydrated rhododendron.
福尔摩斯 瞧这个图案
Holmes. Look at the crest.
李奥丹和布莱克伍德是一伙的
Reordan was working with, Blackwood.
那是当然
Of course he was.
问题是什么目的
Question is, to what end.
不管他在搞什么 显然成功了
Whatever he was working on, clearly suceeded.
怎么说
How so?
不然他还死不了啊
Otherwise, he'd still alive.
所以艾德勒小姐才会急于要找到他
Which is why Miss Adler is so desperate to find him.
对
Yes.
我有一样东西没闻出来
There's something I can't quite put my finger on.
棉花糖 糖浆
Is it candy floss? Molasses.
枫蜜 啊 大麦糖
Maple syrup. Ah, barley sugar.
太妃苹果(左边打手手里拿的)
Toffee apple.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
看你们这身行头
Judging by your arsonist tool kit
你们是来烧房子销毁证据的
You're here to burn down the building and estinguish all the evidence therein
稍等片刻 小子们
Just one minute boys..
噢 Draga
Oh, Draga!
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem?
肉
Meat...
还是土豆
or potatoes?
十分钟到了
My 10 minutes are up.
稍等片刻
我不赶时间
你还好吧
You alright?
你等一下
Come!
福尔摩斯
Holmes.
那是啥
What is that?
我也不知道
小子 来啊
谁派你来的?
你清楚得很
替个死人干活
你还真是奇怪
他死而复生了
不管有没有复活
告诉我他在哪儿
比起你和你的玩具
有些事值得敬畏多了
小兔崽子 跑吧
没问题
福尔摩斯
Holmes!
亲爱的华生
Watson...
你都干了些什么啊
What have you done?
我整夜没睡
I haven't slept all night.
眨都没眨一眼
Not a whink.
我怎么会这样
Why I ever believed...
不去和亲家喝茶 反而
that I would get to have tea with Mary's parents? is beyond me
被你说服跟你走了
having been talked into going with you.
我们遇袭了 伙计 那是自卫
We were set upon man, it was self-defense.
我看了我的笔记 里头有我们过去七个月的丰功伟绩
I've been reviewing my notes, of our exploits over the last seven months.
你知道我得出什么结论
would you like to know my conclusion?
我脑子绝对是进水了
I am psychologically disturbed.
怎么说
How so?
你故意不让我知道你的计划
Why else would I be continually led into situations
我为什么还傻乎乎跟着你跑
where you delibrately, withhold your plans from me?
为什么
Why else?
你之前可没抱怨过我的作风
You never complained about my methods before.
- 不是抱怨 - 不是
- I'm not complaining. - You're not?
- 那是什么 - 我
- What do you call this? - How...
我哪儿抱怨了 我从不呛声
How am I complaining? I never complain, when do I
你半夜三更练琴我有抱怨过吗
ever complain about you practicing the violin at three in the morning.
你不讲卫生 把屋子搞得一团糟
Or your mess, your general lack of hygiene
还偷走我所有衣服我有抱怨过吗
or the fact that you steal all my clothes.
我们说好了的
We have a barter system.
你朝我屋子放火我有抱怨过吗
When do I complain about you setting fire to my room?
- 我们的屋子 - 那些屋子
- Our rooms. - The rooms,
你拿我的狗当实验品我抱怨过吗
When do I ever complain that you experiment on my dog?
- 那是我们的狗 - 看你干的好事
- Our dog! It's our dog. - On the... the dog!
你还破坏我和玛丽的感情 我很生气
But I do take issue, is your campaign to sabatage my relationship to Mary.
我理解
I understand.
- 是吗 - 当然
- You do? - I do.
- 你理解个屁 - 你太累了
- I don't think you do. - You're overly tired.
- 是的 - 你有点太敏感了
- Yes. - You're feeling a bit sensitive.
我没有敏感
I'm not sensitive.
你需要好好休息
What you need is to rest.
我哥迈克罗夫特 在奇切斯特附近有个小庄园
My brother, Mycroft, has a small estate near Chichester.
美丽的草坪
Beautifull grounds...
- 咱哥俩去好好享受下 - 咱们
- We could throw a land on the spit... - We?
福尔摩斯 就算是去郊游 我也是和未婚妻一起去
Holmes, if I were to go to the country it would be with my future wife.
当然 如果你
Well certainly, if you must...
我和玛丽去 没你啥事
No not you, Mary and I.
- 你 - 我不受欢迎吗
- You are not... - What? Invited?
我去我亲哥的庄园小憩都不成吗 华生
Why would I be not invited to my own brothers country home, Watson?
- 你还讲不讲道理啊 - 你个非人类
- Now you are not making any sense! - You're not human!
- 约翰·华生 - 在这
- John Watson? - Yes.
你被保释了
You bail has been posted.
玛丽
Mary!
没你的份
Just Watson.
你最好能在早餐前被保出去 我的兄弟们都饿坏了
I hope you get bail by breakfast, because my boys, are getting hungry.
闪开 闪开
Back off! Back off!
侍者说“我可以拉下您的凳子吗”
To which the barman says: "may I push in your stool?".
你出来
Right you, you're out..
- 下次继续讲 - 很荣幸 福尔摩斯先生
- Until next time. - It's always a pleasure, Mr. Holmes.
你来得真及时 雷斯垂德 我快没笑话可讲了
Thank God you're here, Lestrade I'd almost ran out of jokes.
你上辈子肯定是个罪犯
In another life, you'd have made an excellent criminal.
你是名出色的警官
Yes, sir and you an excellent policemen.
Tomsky 谢了
Tomsky! Thank you.
你可以解释一下吗
Now please tell me you have answers.
适当的时候 雷斯垂德
All in good time, Lestrade.
适当的时候 为什么非要我们 猜你在想些啥
All in good time? what is this some parlour game where we have to guess what you're thinking.
恐慌的公众要求知情权
I've got a public in frenzy out there
不尽快查明真相的话
and if you don't fill me in,
我就把你扔回去和那些赌徒玩个够
I'll have you in there playing Victoria and Albert quicker than a bookies runner
把自己弄干净点 好去见人
Now, clean up and make yourself presentable.
要见谁
For whom?
上头来人了
Friends in high places.
是他们把你保出来的
They're the ones who bailed you out.
很抱歉 先生
I'm terribly sorry to inconvene you, sir.
不过你必须戴上头罩
But I'm going to have to put this on you.
福尔摩斯先生 很抱歉 用这种方式把你请来
Mr. Holmes, apologies for summoning you like this.
你一定很想知道自己在哪 以及我的身份吧
I'm sure it's quite a mystery as to where you are and who I am?
关于我在哪这个问题
As to where I am...
经过查宁路口和霍尔博街的时候 我确实有些分不清方向
I was admitedly lost for a moment, between Charing Cross and Holborn,
但经过南福特山的面包店时 我又搞清楚了方向
but I was saved by the Bread shop on Southford Hill.
只有那个店会在面包里放入 某种特殊的法国奶浆
The only baker to use the certain french glaze on a sage
随后马车又左右颠簸
after that the carriage fought left and right
来到了舰队街
until bump the Fleet conduit
至于你的身份嘛 思考这个问题
And as to who you are? that took every ounce of my not
倒费了一些心思
inconsiderable experience.
你桌上的信是寄给托马斯先生的
The letters on your desk were addressed to a Sir Thomas Rodrum.
他是首席法官
Lord Chief Justice. That would be the official title
至于你是谁 就是另一个问题了
Who you really are... is of course another matter entirely.
从你戒指上的圣牛图来看
Judging by the sacred ox on your ring.
你就是四圣会的神秘头目吧
You're the secret head of the Temple of the Four Orders
这儿就是总部所在地
in who's headquarters we now sit.
应该在圣詹姆斯广场的西北角
Located, north-west corner St. James square I think
我全都知道了 为啥还费心蒙我眼睛呢
That's the mystery, the only mystery is to why you bothered to blind fold me at all.
呃 照章办事罢了
Yes... well, standard procedure I suppose.
我们找对人了 先生们
I dare say we have the right man, gentlemen.
歇洛克·福尔摩斯
Sherlock Holmes.
美国大使史坦迪 以及内政大臣柯瓦德阁下
U.S. Ambassador Standish and Lord Coward, the home secetary.
我想你一定知道我们组织的一些情况吧
I suppose you already have some notion as to the practices of our order.
当然 非常有趣
Yes. They are practically intresting.
你可以持怀疑态度
Be as sceptical as you like.
但几百年来 我们的这个秘密组织 为世界和平做出了巨大的贡献
but our secret system has steered the world to good for centuries.
危险在于 它也可以助纣为虐
There danger is they can also be used for more nefarious purposes.
有人称之为“黑暗艺术” 或是“真实的魔法”
What some call the dark arts or practical magic.
我们知道你不相信魔法 福尔摩斯先生
We know you don't believe in magic Mr. Holmes
也不指望你理解我们的信仰
We don't expect you to share our faith
但请理解我们的恐惧
merely our fears.
眼下 恐惧这个东西
fear is the most infectious condition.
是最具传染性的
In this instance.
您是对自己孩子的恐惧
fear of your own child.
布莱克伍德是您儿子
Blackwood is your son
你们俩有着一样的虹膜 罕见的深绿色 钻石状的淡褐色花线
You have the same irises, a rare dark green, the diamond shaped hazel flex
还有着一样的外耳 这是直系血亲才会遗传的
together with the identical outer ears or pinner, which are only past down through direct blood line
有可能是兄弟
which makes by necessity either brothers
不过现在看来 父子关系更为可能
or in this case, more likely father and son.
很少有人知道这一点
Very few people have paraded that information.
我们必须保密
And we'd want to keep it that way.
他是在组织的仪式上怀上的
He was concieved during one of our rituals.
他母亲不是我妻子
His mother wasn't my wife.
她有着同样的信仰 也是一名出色的法师
But she shared our beliefs. She was a powerfull practitioner.
她生下孩子后就去世了
though not enough to survive giving birth to him.
他在各处散播死亡
Death followed him where ever he went.
那五个女孩并不是唯一的牺牲品
Those five girls were not the first to be butchered.
他杀了很多女孩来增强自己力量
He killed many more to use them to enhance his powers.
当然 没有证人 但我们知道一切
No one could prove anything of course, but we already knew.
他是个祸害
The boy was a curse.
我们尝试过阻止他 但无济于事
We'd done our best to stop him ourselves, but its not enough.
他的力量日益增长
His power grows daily.
复活就是证明
His resurection is evidence of that.
他接下来要做的将更为危险
But what he does next will be far more dangerous.
秘密都在这本咒书中 这是他能量的来源
The secret lies in the book of spells. This is the source of his power.
他要召唤神秘力量 改变这个世界
His going to raise a force that will alter the very course of the world.
我想让你阻止他
I want you to find him and stop him before he does.
我们将提供你所需的一切
We'll give you any assisatnce that we can.
作为内政大臣 我有权力调动警力
As home secretary, I have a considerable influence over the police.
- 我明白 - 那么
- Oh, yes - So...
开个价吧
Name your price?
既然我现在是给各位做顾问 我就有权选择顾客
Well a great benefit to the social deficit. I, can pick and choose my clients.
这个案子 我接了
Consider it done, I'll stop him.
不过 不是为了你 也不会开什么价
But not for you. And certainly not for a price.
我倒有个疑问 托马斯
I do have a parting query sir, Thomas.
什么疑问
What is that?
如果他其它的亲人都死了
We the rest of his family dead...
你还能活多久呢
how long do you expect to survive?
好好想想吧
Food for thought.
你开这个会更在行些吧
Well perhaps you'll have better luck opening that.
Margot 58 彗星葡萄酒啊
Margot '58. comet vintage.
好神奇啊 彗星还会影响酒的...
How fascinating that a astronomical event can effect the quality...
那件拜托你的案子咋样了
How is it going with our case that you refused to take.
酒的质量
...wine.
噢 我进死胡同了
Or I've hit a dead end. Literally.
你要找的人被埋在布莱克伍德的坟墓里
I found your man. He's buried in Blackwood's tomb.
还要继续查吗
If you still need him.
天啊
Oh dear...
希望顾客不会来要求我退钱
I hope my client doesn't come looking for a refund.
你的顾客是位教授吧
He's a professor, isn't he?
我没看到正脸 但看到衣服上的粉笔灰了
I couldn't see his face, but I spotted a bit of chalk on his tappan.
我还不知道有哪位教授 会随身带一把如此精致的手枪
I've never known a professor to carry a gun, and on such a clever contraption.
原来戴眼罩的是你 厉害...
Eyepatch. Nice touch...
那么案子结束了
So... case closed.
所以你现在只是顺路过来拜访
Which makes this a social visit.
不 我是来告诉你 事情已经非你所能掌控 艾琳
No. It's you're in over your head Irene, visit.
杀害李奥丹的凶手有意隐藏行踪
Who ever killed, Reardon they were covering their tracks,
你就是他们的下一个目标
which means that you're the next loose end that needs to be snipped.
放松点
Let it breathe.
没有我搞不定的事情
I've never been in over my head.
远走高飞吧 那是你最擅长的
Leave now, dissapear. You're good at that.
留下来的话最好接受安全保护
Or stay. And volunteer for protective custody.
要是我有危险 你也逃不掉
If I'm in danger, so are you.
跟我走吧
Come with me.
我们就彼此信任一回 行不
What if we trusted each other.
听着 我要带你去火车站
You're not listening. I'm taking you, to either a railway station
或是警察局
or the policestation.
那么
So...
你选哪个
What is it to be?
你来决定吧
You decide, which will it be?
让你放松些嘛
I told you to let it breathe.
尝到彗星的味道了吗
Can you taste the comet?
为啥不跟我一起走呢
Why couldn't you just come away with me?
女士 请保持冷静
Madam, I need you to remain calm.
相信我 我不是坏人 这个枕头底下
Trust me, I'm a professional. but underneath this pillow
藏着能让我自由的钥匙
lies the key to my release.
她完全误会了我的意思
Of course, she misinterpreted my intention entirely.
- 人之常情嘛 - 所以我觉得现代宗教狂热很烦人
- Naturally sir. - Thats why I find this modern religious fellow so troubling.
根本就不包容误会嘛
There's no latitude for misunderstandings.
别满嘴跑火车了 先生
It runs right over reason, sir.
侍女曾经是很善解人意的
And chambermaids were once such a liberal breed.
我妻子就曾经当过侍女 先生
My wife's a chambermaid, sir.
还好 她对你还算客气 要不我们就不可能找到你了
Anyhow, it's a good thing she was a friend, otherwise we may never have found you.
警长一整个早上都呆在贝克街呢
The inspector's been over at Baker Street himself this morning, sir.
我妻子的事 只是开个玩笑
Just joking about the wife, sir.
我们检查过了 门窗没有被撬开的迹象
We've checked everything. There's no sign of a break in
管家也没听到什么异样声音
and the butler didn't hear a thing.
尸体在浴缸里 死不瞑目
So body in the bath tub, his eyes were wide open
唯一失踪的东西是
and the only thing missing was...
他的戒指
His ring, sir.
干嘛要把水放干啊
Why did you drain the water?
对死者的尊重
Out of common decency.
罪犯当道 请保持理智
Crime is common. Logic, is rare.
我们应该做的是捉住罪犯 而不是安慰一具尸体
The decent thing to do is catch the killer, not to provide conflict to the cause.
那是啥
What is that?
是茉莉浴盐
Jasmine bath salt, sir.
那原本应该是装在一个大容器里的
Super. Probably comes from a larger container.
大概是放在储藏室里的
It would either be in the pantry.
温暖又干燥的地方 或是放在有通风口的柜橱里
High up where it's warm and dry. Or in a linen cupboard with a vent.
警官 你最好检查一下后窗那块
Oh and constable, you could do worse than to check the
看有没有脚印啥的
ground under the rear window for any signs of footprints
线索 线索 线索 没线索我咋办案啊
data, data, data. I can not make bricks without clay.
查尔斯
Charles?
在柜橱还是储藏室里
Was it in the cupboard or the pantry.
在储藏室找到的
It was in the pantry, sir.
这玩意用啥做的
I don't know what to make of this.
匠心独运啊
Wxcellent work.
拜拜
Adieu.
这算什么 柯瓦德
What's the meaning of this, Coward?
干嘛要开这个会
Why have you called this meeting?
托马斯爵士死了
Sir Thomas is dead.
我提名布莱克伍德为四圣会领导
I nominate Lord Blackwood as head of the Order.
你疯了吗
Have you lost your mind?
你难道不知道他的可怕
You know damn well what his capable of.
他当然知道
Of course he does.
所以咱们才会
That's why we're here.
全体聚集于此
That's why, we're all here.
我的力量和财产 均是为了一个目的
My powers and my assets were given to me for one purpose.
荣华富贵只是表面的
Magnificent was a simple purpose.
我们要开创新的未来
To create a new future.
由我们统治的未来
A future ruled... by us.
明天正午 我们将谱写新的历史篇章
Tomorrow at noon, we take the first step towards a new chapter in our history.
魔术将引领我们前行
Magic will lead the way.
一旦英格兰人民见识到我们的力量
Once the people of England see our new found power
他们都会臣服
they'll bow down in fear.
大西洋那边 有一块大陆曾是我们的殖民地
Across the Atlantic, lies a colony that was once ours.
我们要收复失地
It will be again.
南北战争使他们内耗严重
The civil war has made them weak.
他们的政府和英国的一样 腐败无能 效率低下
Their government is as corrupt and ineffective as ours.
把它收回是天经地义
So we'll take it back.
我们要重新创造世界
We will remake the world.
开创未来
Create the future.
这些人都支持我 Standish
These men are with me, Standish.
你呢
But... are you?
你想 都别想
No, sir. I am not.
你的力量
These powers that you're playing with...
没人能控制得住
no man, can control.
先生们 虽然你们不想 但必须有人阻止他
Well gentlemen... Someone has to stop them
你逃不了的
even if you won't.
如果我是你 就不会开枪
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
别害怕 先生们
Gentlemen... don't be afraid.
我们有神力护体
As you can see, we are protected.
请歃酒为盟
Come... drink your allegience here.
你有权调动警察 把他们都利用起来吧
You control the police, now use them.
我不知道你在
I didn't know you were here.
这房间不是你的了 介意我使用一下不
Since this room is no longer yours, do you mind if I utilise it?
随意
Be my guest.
- 进来吧 - 把他放哪
- In here chaps. - Where shall we put him, sir?
随你们怎么放
Anywhere's fine.
这是谁
Who is he?
在李奥丹房间里想杀你的那个人
His the one who tried to kill you at Reardon's lodgings.
他Draga被撞断了脖子
I suppose his neck didn't survive the impact of Draga landing on him.
谢谢你那次救了我
Yes... Thanks for that by the way.
庆幸的是 这家伙的尸体还有些用途
But there is still some consolation in the knowledge that he can still be of service to his fellow man.
肘上沾着血
Elbow is now stained with blood.
不过是他受伤之前沾上的
But it's older than his own injuries.
不是动物的血 也不是人的血...
Not if it's not human. There's an odd butcher. Let me see...
黄色火焰 绿色灰烬
Yellow Flame. Green bursts.
他是个工厂工人
An industrial worker.
有煤炭和淤泥的痕迹
Coal. Hint of silt.
裤子上的污渍 说明他是在
And the stains on his trousers, should put him squarely in...
九榆树
Nine Elms.
啥
Sorry what?
你要找的地方是 九榆树
The area you're looking for is, Nine Elms.
你记得我把那本书放哪了么
Do you remember where I put the Lord's registerer of members intrests?
在梯子上面
On the step ladder.
布莱克伍德在腐蚀人们的灵魂
Blackwood was involved in everything that's corrosive to the spirit.
Woolidge军火库
Woolidge Arsenal.
莱姆豪斯化学工厂
Limehouse Chemical Works.
很可能是河边的一家工厂
Probably be a factory by the river.
啥
What's that?
当我没说
Never mind.
你知道我的橄榄球在哪吗
You don't know where my rugby ball went do you?
不知道
No, not a clue.
昆斯亥特屠宰场
Queensithe slaughterhouse
九榆树
Nine Elms.
一家在河边的工厂
A factory by the river.
很好 华生 我们会找到布莱克伍德的
Well done, Watson. That should lead us right to Blackwood.
活要见人 死要见尸
Dead or Alive.
不是“我们”
Not us.
是“你”
You.
好吧
Yes...
继续咬文嚼字吧 伙计
Just a figure of speech, old boy.
他故意留下的
He's left it there on purpose.
再加点煤 医生
More coal doctor.
真不赖啊
That's a good one.
很高兴看见你们在“努力工作”
Glad to see you two are working hard then.
别闲着好不好
And I thought you were trying to be discrete.
你在海军一天都干不下去
You would not last one day in the navy.
福尔摩斯 你确定
Holmes, are you sure that there is no
这是你能找到的最好的船
alternative means of water transportaion, than that.
我敢打赌 没人比他更熟悉伦敦的水路了
I guarantee you nobody knows London's waterways better.
Tanners简直就是一条鱼
Tanners practically a fish himself.
他醉醺醺的样子确实像鱼
At least he certainly drinks like one.
挺幽默的嘛 医生
Oh you've found your sense of humour, doctor.
不过太损人啦
If only just a sense.
还是我来吧 这活儿还是有诀窍的
I better take over. A bit tricky down here.
快走
Come on...
- 似曾相识 - 没错
- Look familiar? - Yep.
少了个侏儒而已
All that's missing is a ginger midget.
他们清理了些东西
They cleared something away from here.
有段时间了
Not minutes ago.
啥东西
Like what?
不清楚 可能是些机械吧
I'm not sure. Something mechanical.
福尔摩斯 看看这个
Holmes, look at this.
- 1:18 - 代表“章”和“节”
- 1:18 - Chapter and verse.
启示录第1章18节 我是存活的
Revelations. 1:18. "I am here liveth
- 又是死亡的 - 我存活的时候更多
- and was dead." - And behold of the life for ever more.
我警告你 福尔摩斯
I warned you, Holmes to accept
这不是你能控制得了的
that this was beyond your control.
也不是你那凡人的脑子所能理解的
Beyond what your rational mind could comprehend.
这是你的“来世”吗
What if this, is the after life that you're having.
我想让你成为见证人
I want you to bear witness.
明天正午 你所认识的世界将会灭亡
Tomorrow, at midday, the world as you know it, will end.
你敢不敢现身 我现在就灭了你
Show me your face and it will be the end of your qorld right now.
节约子弹 华生
Save the bullets, Watson.
送你份小礼
A gift for you.
刚才谁说节约子弹来着
What was that about saving bullets?
她跟踪你来到这 福尔摩斯
She followed you here, Holmes.
想眼睁睁看着小羊羔被屠宰吗
You reared your lamb to slaughter.
接着
Holmes!
小心点 别伤着
This game was designed to hurt.
华生
Watson!
这里还很热 华生
It's warm in here, Watson!
超过你能力范围了吗 亲爱的
In over your head yet, darling?
- 坚持住 - 我做不到
- Hold on there! - I can't.
让我帮你减轻点重量
Let me take your weight.
把腿伸直了 老伙计
Hold the leg up, old boy.
我一直搞不定这种吊锁
These jamming locks always give me trouble.
但愿这把锯子并不锋利
To bad a saw.
没关系 我们有的是时间
No matter. We have plenty of time.
福尔摩斯
Holmes...
- 这没效果啊 - 保持冷静
- It's not working. - Keep calm.
福尔摩斯 快点
Holmes! Hurry up.
别激动
You're not getting excited...
去把阀门关上
Turn of that valve.
听我倒数 往下压 三
And we bounce in... Three
二
...two,
一
...one.
谢谢
Thank you.
我去追布莱克伍德
I'm gonna get after, Blackwood.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们该去帮医生的忙了
We should go help the doctor.
福尔摩斯
Holmes!
先生 柯瓦德签发了逮捕令要抓你
Lord. Coward has issued a warrant for your arrest.
华生还活着 离开这 先生 走吧
Watson's alive. Just get out of here, sir. Go.
火车会准点开吗
Will the train be departing on time?
晚点了 女士
The train's been delayed, madam.
但应该不会太久
Shouldn't be long now though.
只有得到我的首肯火车才会开
The train will depart when I tell it too.
你想要离任也需得到我的允许
And you will leave my employment, when I allow you too.
我已经履行了契约
I fulfilled my contract.
我找到李奥丹了
I found Reorden.
他在苏格兰场的停尸间里
He's in Scotland Yard's mortuary.
我完成我的工作了
So that's me finished.
你的工作是操控福尔摩斯对你的感觉
Your job was to munipulate, Holmes' feelings for you.
而不是屈从于他们
Not succomb to them.
你完全没有没履行你的职责
You have fulfilled nothing.
我要李奥丹给布莱克伍德制作的东西
I want what, Reardon was making for Blackwood.
完成你的工作 不然下一个死的将是歇洛克?福尔摩斯
finish the job, or the next dead body will be of Sherlock Holmes.
外科医生应该很快就到
The surgeon should be along shortly.
他现在应该能好好休息了
He should be able to rest now.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你这就竭尽全力了
Is that the best you can do?
目前来说是的
Yes for now.
我得去照顾其它病人了
I must attend to my other patients.
医生
Doctor...
Doctor!
拜托了
Please!
我知道你和我一样关心他
I know that you care for him as much as I do.
这不是你的责任 这是他自己的选择
This is not your responsibility, It was his choice.
他说受这伤是值得的
He'd say it was worth the wounds.
解决好这件事
Solve this.
不计任何代价
Whatever it takes.
是布莱克伍德 先生
It's Lord Blackwood, sir.
没什么我做不到的
I've never been in over my head.
这虽与我无关 但我建议你别管这案子
It's nothing to do with me, but I'd advise you to leave the case alone.
你并没认真对待此事 福尔摩斯
You're not taking this seriously are you, Holmes.
我告诉过你 这事远远超过了你的能力范围
I told you to accept, his was belond your control
明日正午 世界将于此刻终结
Tomorrow at mid-day, the world will end.
福尔摩斯
Holmes.
你和我 踏入一场 即将扭转世界的漫漫旅程
You and I, are bound on a journey that will twist the very fabric of nature.
好好想清楚 福尔摩斯
Steal your mind, "Holmes.
他将召唤出一股 能彻底改变世界的力量
He will raise a force that will change the very course of the world.
他的力量会增长
His power grows.
这是他力量的来源
This is the source of his power.
我需要你
I need you.
秘密就藏在魔法书之中
The secret lies in the book of spells.
还将有三人死去
Three more will die...
无论如何你救不了他们
and there's nothing you can do to save them.
我们知道你不相信魔法
We know you don't believe in magic.
李奥丹在和布莱克伍德合作
Reardon was working with Blackwood.
唯一不见的是他的戒指
The only thing missing was his ring.
放弃吧 福尔摩斯
Give up, Holmes.
这个谜题你解答不了
This is a riddle you can not solve.
早上好
Good morning.
现在你得工作了
Now, you need to work.
这副图看起来眼熟吗
Familliar artwork?
你看起来真不错
You look gorgeous.
我就知道你不会走的
Some how, I knew you wouldn't leave.
你上了报纸头版
You made the front page.
只有名字 没登照片
Only a name, and no picture?
看起来你需要边躲避司法边工作了
So it looks like, you'll be needing to work outside the law now,
这正是我的专长
and that's my area of expertise.
我已经感觉安全多了
I feel safer already.
你看起来恢复得很快
You seem to be making a rapid recoverey.
是的
Yes...
我自己把弹片取出来了
I took this shrapnel out myself.
玛丽说给我看病的医生很差劲
Mary said I had a lousy doctor.
我 我只是
Well I'm... I'm just so...
很高兴你 能和我们在一起
very glad that you're um... well, with us.
现在你已经舒舒服服的坐好了 那我就要开始说了
Now that you're sitting comfortably, I shall begin.
我起初的调查面太狭隘了
My initial approach was far to narrow.
布莱克伍德邀请我去 本顿维尔监狱的时候
When Blackwood invited me to Pentonville prison
他建议我扩宽眼界
he suggested I widen my gaze.
至少我刚刚做到了这点
and at minimum, I have done just that.
实际上 我可能刚刚解决了 上千年来神学研究上的分歧
In fact, I may well have reconciled thousand's of years of theological disparities.
但这个就留到下次再说吧
But that's for another time.
布莱克伍德的方法 主要基于一种神秘的仪式
Blackwood's method is based on a ritualistic mystical system
这种仪式已经由四圣会沿用了几个世纪
that's been employed by the Temple of the Four Order for centuries.
为了能完全深入的了解这个仪式
To fully understand the system, to get inside it,
我重塑了地穴中被打断的那个仪式
I recreated the ceremony we interuppted at the crypt,
在下还稍微做了点改进
with a few enhancements of my own.
我的旅程带我到达了 比我想象中更遥远的兔子洞
My journey took me further down the rabbit hole than I intended
尽管弄脏了我那毛茸茸的白尾巴
and though I don'tneed my fluffy white tail.
但我受到了启发
I have emerged, enlightened.
直接控制帝权的兄弟会
The fraternity who decidedly control the empire
崇信所有国王 法老和古代帝王的信仰
who share the belief of kings, pharaohs and emperors of old
认为斯芬克斯是通往另一个维度的大门
that the Sphinx was a door to another dimension.
是一条通往无上力量的大道
A gateway to immeasurable power.
它由四个部分组成
It's made up of four parts.
狮足 牛尾 鹰翼
The foot of a lion, the tail of an ox, the wings of an eagle
和人首
and the head of a man.
我在托马斯爵士的密室里 找到了一根牛骨
In sir Thomas's secret chamber, I found a bone of an ox
狮牙 鹰羽 以及人的毛发
the tooth of a lion, the feather of an eagle and a hair of a man.
把地图拿出来
Map.
这些星型记号代表了被杀的五个女孩
The points of the stars represent the the five murdered girls
但现在重要的是这个叉
but the cross is what were now intrested in.
有一种被广泛接受的说法 认为大城市中的建筑
It's a wildly held belief, that within the architecture of the great cities
是仪式的解碼参考
are coded references to the system
自从布莱克伍德从坟墓中复活之后 他杀了三个人
Since he rose from the grave, Blackwood's killed three men.
每起谋杀案都发生在 和神殿直接有关的地方
Each murder was committed at a location that has a direct connection with the temple
也就是和仪式相关之处
therefore a system .
李奥丹 那个黄头发的侏儒
Reardon, the ginger midget.
代表人类 我们在这找到了他的尸体
represents man. We found his body here.
托马斯爵士 圣会的头目 拥有圣牛指环
Sir Thomas... master of the temple, wore the ox ring.
他死在这里
He died here.
史坦迪 出使美国的代表 一百多年来
Standish, the ambassador to the U.S.. Where the eagle has been a national
鹰都是美国的象征
emblem over a hundred years .
他死在四圣会的总部
The headquarters of the Temple of the Four Order is where he died,
也就是这
this here.
相应地 地图将告诉我们 布莱克伍德终极行动的所在地
Corresponded, the map will tell us the location of Blackwood's final act
现在我们有了人 牛 鹰 只缺狮子了
So we have man, the ox, eagle, only the lion remaining.
就在这里
Right here.
是国会
Parliament.
好了 你们四个留在这 剩下的跟我来
Alright you four stay here and the rest of you come with me.
这边走
Right this way.
女士优先
Ladies first.
照着这些指示做
Follow these instructions.
好啊 好啊 好啊...
Hello, hello, hello...
魔鬼出现了吗
Did the devil turn up?
没关系
Well never mind.
还有好东西等着你
You've got the next best thing.
请原谅 大人 我知道这么做不合正统
Beg your pardon my lord, I know it's unorthodox
但这位福尔摩斯先生 对你 以及四圣会
But Mr. Holmes here has been making some serious accusations about you
做出了严重的指控
and The Order.
我明白了
I see.
至少这解释了你是怎么当上警长的
At least this solves the great mystery of how you became inspector.
抱歉 大人
Excuse me, my lord.
但我很久之前就想这么做了
But I've been wanting to that for a long time.
警长 现在离我下个预约 还有五分钟的时间
Well inspector, have five minutes before my next engagement.
不如你直接交代阴谋
So why don'tyou engrail me with your stories of conspiracy
谢谢 雷斯垂德
Thank you Lestrade.
大人
My lord...
我很好奇 柯瓦德 你是协助布莱克伍德杀了所有人
I'm curious, Coward. Did you help Blackwood in all his murders.
还只是参与了被我制止的那起
or just the one I prevented?
你穿的这些手工鞋很不错
Very distinctive, those hand made shoes of yours.
但质量一向取决于作品的疏漏之处
But the price of quality is often the leaking print they leave
话虽如此 我不得不承认 我实在是落于人后了
Nonetheless I confess to being completely outmatched.
调查中所能得到的结论甚少
I could deduce very little from my investigation.
幸运的是 没什么比
Fortunately there's nothing more stimulating than a
难办的案子更能鼓舞人的了
case where everything goes against you.
你今天中午打算杀害多少国会议员?
How many members of parliament do you intend to murder at noon today.
人 牛 鹰 狮 狮子是指国会 对不对
Man, ox, eagle, lion. The lion's parliament isn't it?
你很聪明
Very clever.
但这不是谋杀 福尔摩斯先生
But it's not murder, Mr. Holmes.
我这是慈悲
It's mercy.
我们将赐予孱弱的大众 以坚强的防卫
We are giving the weak masses a strong Shepard.
你看不出来吗 这是为了他们自己
Don't you see, it's for their own...
我不觉得 但我不在乎你的想法
No. But I don't care much what you think.
我只是想知道布莱克伍德 最终仪式的所在地
I just simply wanted to know the location of Blackwood's final ceremony.
现在你已经告诉我了
And now you've given it to me.
我什么都没告诉你
I've told you nothing.
但你的衣服在无形中出卖了你
But your clothes say infinitely more than you could ever hope.
你靴子上沾的泥指明了你的所到之处
The mud smeared on your boots from where you'vee been walking.
你膝盖上粘上的红砖灰 指明了你的跪拜之处
A touch of red brick dust on your knee from where you'vee been kneeling.
你拇指上的绷带指明了你的宣誓之地
A small bandage on your thumb from where you'vee been vowing.
排泄物的微弱气味 指明了你的脚踏之地
A faint aroma of excrement from where you'vee been standing.
不到一小时之前
You and Blackwood laid the final toches to your ceremony in the sewers
你和布莱克伍德在国会下方的下水道
beneath parliament
最后一次碰面
less than an hour ago.
上下两院将在今天开会
Both houses meet today.
全部政府成员都将到场
The whole government will be present.
你选择做布莱克伍德的敌人 真是可惜 福尔摩斯
It's a shame you made an enemy out of Blackwood, Holmes.
你本可以成为一个很有价值的盟友
You would have made a valuable ally.
当智慧无法为智者带来益处时
How terrible is wisdom.
智慧还有何用呢
when it brings no profit to the wise.
我们在中午吸收能量
We take power at noon.
那没时间可浪费了
Then isn't anytime to waste then.
对不对
Guess not?
都说他会从天窗出来了 伙计
Told you he'llbe coming out of that top window soldier boy.
他绝不可能从露台出来
There isn't any way he'llbe coming out of that terrace.
确切的说那可不是天窗 对吧 伙计
Technically that isn'tthe top window, is it Sailor boy.
- 那是什么? - 是中间的窗户
- Where was he? - It's the middle window.
不管怎么说 你应该会很高兴知道 雷斯垂德把角色诠释地很完美
Anyway, you'llbe pleased to know that Lustrate played in his role perfectly
实际上 我觉得他挺乐在其中的
Actually, I think I rather enjoyed it.
但愿你知道自己在干什么 福尔摩斯
I hope you know what you're doing, Holmes.
这是钥匙
Here's the key.
你从柯瓦德那拿到需要的东西了吗
You got what you needed from, Coward?
拿到了 我轻轻松松的 把他熏出了房间
Yes, I smoked him out of the room with ease.
- 泰勒 - 什么事
- Taylor? - Yes?
如果可以的话 船长 带我们上桥
If you would captain, take us onto the bridge
港口那边 大约在100码之外有一条隧道 能把我们带到下水道
Port side. proximately 100 yards beyond that you will find a tunnel, that leads us to the sewers.
这就去 先生
Alright, sir.
布莱克伍德从地狱返回 在这片土地上施了咒语
Blackwood's come back from hell and laid a curse upon this land
看着 布莱克伍德的魔术揭秘
Behold, Blackwood's magic revealed.
怎么做
What does it do?
是化学武器
It's a chemical weapon.
首款型号
The first of its kind.
你怎么推断出的
You deduced that, how?
凭我口袋里的东西
From my pocket.
我在屠宰场剪了条普通老鼠的尾巴
I snipped this of a rather common rat at the slaughterhouse.
注意这些蓝色斑点
Notice the bluish discolouration.
轻微的杏仁苦味是氰化物残留的痕迹
The faint smell of almonds, and traces of cyanide.
现在我们知道小矮人究竟是什么用途了
Now we know what the ginger midget was working on.
- 它会改变战争的局势 - 是的 杀死很多人
- It will revolutionise warfare. - Yes killing a lot of people.
现还有7分钟就到中午了 我们怎么做
Now, there's 7 minutes until noon. What are we gonna do?
你的女神更喜欢直接的
She loves an entrance, your muse.
射他 马上
Shoot him! Now please!
议员们 议员们
My lords! My lords.
时间已到了 请相信的人留下来
Time has come for any of those who believe, to remain.
请看 布莱克伍德公爵
Behold... Lord Blackwood.
你们似乎很吃惊
You seem surprised.
我从远方的坟墓中归来 是为了改变英格兰的命运
I have returned from beyond the grave to fulfil England's destiny.
并扩大这个伟大帝国的疆域
and extend the boundaries of this great empire.
听听外面那些乌合之众的喊叫
Listen to the rabble outside.
听听
Listen...
这些恐惧吧
to the fear.
我会用恐惧作为武器来控制他们...
I will use that as a weapon to control them...
然后控制全世界
and then the world.
我从来没见过这样的东西 看这个
I've never seen anything like it. Look at this.
是专门设计用作防止我们破坏的装置
It's specifically designed to prevent us from disarming it.
这些部件似乎是用来接受某种信号
These components seem to be specifically designed to receive some sort of signal.
电磁波
Electromagnetic waves?
一经触发 电极就会发出电荷
When triggered, the electrodes will send a charge
把化学药品转化成气体
converting the chemial into gas.
然后这些气体会在管道中扩散
And the gas will travel up that shaft
经由通风系统直接进入议会大厅
and filter through the ventilation system that leads directly to parliament.
用不了几秒 即使最精壮的人也会窒息而死
Within seconds, the administration the most powerfull men in the world will be choking to death
布莱克伍德肯定有个信号发射器
Blackwood must have some sort of transmitter
可远程遥控这个装置
that connects them remotely.
仅剩3分10秒
Three minutes and ten seconds.
我将开创一个千秋万代
I will create an empire that will endure for a millennia
不可战胜 永恒不朽的帝国
Indestructible and eternal.
走 快走
Move it! Move it!
我们无需解除装置运行 只要移除汽缸就可
We don't have to actually disarm the device, we just have to remove the cylinders.
对
Yes.
可惜这里被焊死了 我们需要制造一个可控爆炸
Except that they're welded in. What we need is a controlled expolsion.
我们需要一个容器导出化学品 用我的烟斗爆破
We need a container to direct the blast my clay pipe should service that ambition
你
想我了吗
真希望你没开枪 艾琳
I rather wish you hadn't done that, Irene.
十二响钟声响起时 我会召唤邪恶的力量
On the twelfth chime, I will summon the dark powers.
支持我的人将会受到保护
All of those who are with me shall be protected.
其它的人 将会灭亡
All others will perish.
借你的烟斗用下
I need your pipe.
打他
Nut him!
新的秩序 即将拉开帷幕
A new order... begins now.
你在等什么
What are you waiting for?
就这样
That.
- 你能搞定吗 - 当然
- Can you manage? - Of course I can.
放松点 我是医生
Relax. I'm a doctor.
你迷路了吗
Did you take a wrong turning somewhere?
我们现在安全了
We're safe now.
想法很有趣
Interesting assessment .
你走吧
Run off.
我不会再抓你了
I won't be chasing you anymore.
请保重
Fair thee well.
我不想再逃亡了
I don't want to run anymore.
我会告诉你真相
I'll tell you everything.
希望你会
I wish you would.
不
No!
根本没什么魔法
There was never any magic.
只是些魔术的障眼法
Only conjuring tricks.
只是简单地收买了一些人
The simplest involves paying people off.
比如在你牢房外假装被施了魔法的狱警
Like the prison guard who pretended to be possessed outside you cell.
剩下就靠的你的名声和其它人的畏惧
Your reputation and the inmates fear did the rest.
还有就是精心的策划
Others required more elaborate preparations.
你的墓穴上面盖的是沙石板
It was sand storm slab that covered your tomb.
在你下葬前就已经敲碎了
You had it broken before your burial
然后你又粘到了一起
then put back together using a mild adhesive.
至于古埃及的秘方 我认为...
An ancient Egyptian recipe, I believe.
是一种鸡蛋和蜂蜜的混合物 雨水很容易就能冲掉
A mixture of egg and honey, that was to be washed away by the rain.
福尔摩斯
Holmes!
至于你父亲溺死在浴缸里的安排
Arranging for your father to drown in his own bathtub
用的是一些现代的科学
required more modern science.
聪明的李奥丹发现了一种可致人瘫痪的东西
Very clever of, Reordan to find a paralytic
这种东西在铜和水的化合物中反应生成
that was activated by the combination of copper and water.
因此当水被排干净之后很难被发现
and therefore was undetectable once the bath water was drained.
对我来说是确实是个挑战
It would have been quite a challenge for me,
还好他用一些倒霉的蟾蜍做过实验
had he not also tested it on some unfortunate amphibian.
史坦迪的死原本是个谜
The death of Standish was a real mystery
直到你使用相同的化合物炸掉码头
until you used the same compound, to blow up the wharf.
一种无臭无味易燃的液体
An odorless, tasteless flammable liquid
而且由一种粉色织品引燃
yet it burned with an unusual pink tissue.
史坦迪进去前以为是雨水淋到身上 对吗
Did Standish mistake it for rain as he entered the temple.
只需一点火星就可点燃
All it took was a spark.
他枪里的子弹被动了手脚
A simple rigged bullet in his gun.
构思精妙
Ingenious.
像所有伟大的演员 你演得惟妙惟肖
Like all great performers, you saved your pierce do r istance for the end.
化学武器是蒸馏氰化物所得
A chemical weapon, distilled from cyanide.
是在猪的肚子里提炼的
and refined in the bellies of swine.
如果启动 议会里你的追随者都会安然无恙
Had it worked, your followers in parliament would have watched unharmed
但他的同僚们都会中毒身亡
as their colleagues were dying around them.
他们不知道你给了他们解药
They didn't know that you'd given them the antidote.
相反都以为是魔法
Instead they would have believed it was magic.
于是你就掌握了最终极的力量
and that you'd harnessed the ultimate power.
然后整个世界都会屈从 因为恐惧是最强大的武器
and the world would have followed in fear, in the most powerfull weapon of all.
你期望这不仅仅是迷信
You'd better hope it's nothing more than superstition,
当你在仪式上精彩的演出后
as you performed all the rituals perfectly.
我会说是跟魔鬼交易了灵魂
The devil's missing its soul, I'd say.
看在上帝的份上 福尔摩斯求我放开我
For god's sake, Holmes cut me loose!
首先 得让世人认清你的真面目
First, the world will see you for what you are.
一个骗子
A fraud.
然后你将被真正地绞死
Then you will be hanged properly this time.
在那之前我还可以做很多事
It's a long journey from here to the rope.
我从来没带着手铐醒来过
I've never woken up in handcuffs before.
我有过
I have.
还是裸体
Naked.
暴风雨就要来了
A storm is coming.
我们还有点时间
Well... we've still got a moment.
- 莫里亚蒂 - 什么
- Moriarty... - What?
这是他的名字
That's his name.
而且他是个教授
And he is a professor.
每个人都有弱点
Everyone has a weak spot.
他抓住了我的弱点
And he found mine.
它究竟是什么
What was it precisely?
请不要低估他
Please don't underestimate him.
他和你一样卓越
He's just as brilliant as you are.
而且更加阴险
and infinitely more devious.
走着瞧吧
We'll see about that.
你会想我吗 歇洛克
You'll miss me, Sherlock?
很遗憾 会
Sadly... yes.
- 下午好 我把笔记放到这个箱子了 先生 - 谢谢
- Afternoon, sir. I put the notebook in this one, sir. - Thank you.
这些是什么 约翰
What's in these, John?
- 草稿 - 草稿
- Scribbles. - Scribbles?
- 笔记 - 这是你的冒险笔记
- Notes. - The're your adventures!
我想读读
I'd like to read them.
怎么了
Come on, what's wrong?
你认为他会最终妥协让你离开吗
I think his finally come to terms of you leaving?
玛丽 看他送给我们的戒指
Mary, look at the ring his given us.
等我五分钟 我们就回家
Now 5 minutes here, and we'll go home.
我们的家
Our home.
小心上楼梯
Carefull on the stairs.
别担心 亲爱的
Don't worry, dear.
自杀不是他的拿手节目 他只是太喜欢恶搞
Suicide is not in his repertoire. He's far to fond of himself for that.
福尔摩斯
Holmes!
下午好
Good afternoon.
我正在推演布莱克伍德 在绞刑中幸存的几率
I was trying to deduce in which the manner Blackwood survived his execution.
这会让思路变得清晰
Clearing your good name as it were.
很奇怪这对我有催眠作用 而且
But it had a surprising suffocating effect on, and
我就像躺在睡神的臂弯里
I was carried off in the hands off, Morpheus
就像蚕蛹在茧里一样 下午好 亲爱的
like a caterpillar in a cocoon. Good afternoon, dear.
继续 福尔摩斯
Get on with it, Holmes.
侩子手在绳结里聪明的藏了个钩子
Cleverly concealed in the hang-mans knot, was a hook
亲爱的 我的腿快要麻了 我想该下来了
Oh dear, I think my legs have fallen asleep I should probably come down.
约翰 我们该把他弄下来吗
John, shouldn't we help him down?
不 不 我不喜欢打断他
No, no, I hate to cut him off midstream.
继续
Carry on.
侩子手给他穿了个特殊的马甲
Well the executioner attached it to a harness.
这样重量就被均匀分散到腰部而且
Thus lowering the weight contributed around the waist and
脖子却完好无损
the neck to remain intact.
上帝 我的脸麻木了
Oh my lord, I can't feel my cheeks.
我们可以在地面上继续吗
Might we continue this at ground level?
你是怎么做到的 福尔摩斯
How did you manage it, Holmes?
我用了吊带 腰带 和一个衣服架钩做成的
I managed it with braces, belts and a coat hook.
华生 我舌头要伸直了 我会继续说 但这样对你没好处
Please, Watson, my tongue is going, I would be of no use to you at all.
- 还会更糟糕吗 - 约翰
- Worse things could happen. - John.
但这些无法解释布莱克伍德没有脉搏
None of this, explains Blackwood's lack of pulse
是的
Right.
现在来解释这个医学之谜
Now the medical mystery.
我们得恢复你的声誉 华生
We must restore your reputation,Watson.
有一种毒药是从杜鹃花蜜中提取出的
There is a toxin refined from the nectar of rhododendron ponticum.
在土耳其近黑海地区非常有名
It's quite infamous in the region of Turkey, near the Black Sea, for it's
因为它能引起显著的死状麻痹
ability to induce an apparently mortal paralysis.
足以制造一种医学假像 误导像你一样的专业医生
Even for a logical and well trained mind, even one as tenacious as your own.
据了解当地
It's known locally as...
格莱斯顿怎么了
What's wrong with Gladston?
狂蜂病
Mad honey's diesease.
他有效地证明了我刚才的描述
His demonstrating the very effects that I just described.
他不介意的
He doesn't mind.
玛丽 别担心 它经历过更惨的
Mary don't worry. he's seen far worse.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes?
医生 玛丽小姐
Doctor, Miss Mary...
打扰了 雷斯垂德警长请你跟我们立刻走一趟
Sorry. Inspector Lestrade asks you come with me right away.
这次又怎么了 克拉基
What is it this time, Clarky?
死者是我们的警员之一 先生
It's one of our sergeants, sir.
你抓住布莱克伍德那天 他从下水道失踪了
He went missing in the sewers the day, you stopped Lord Blackwood.
管道清理工今天上午发现了他的尸体 先生
I'mafraid the sewage workers found his body just this morning, sir
我相信那名警官是第一个赶到现场的
We believe the sergeant, was the first man at the scene...
有什么要帮忙的吗 长官
Can I help you, offcer?
被击中了头部
Shot in the head.
是小口径子弹吗
Was it a small caliber bullet?
是的
Yes.
眉毛上有灼烧粉末吗
Was there powdered burns on his eyebrows?
是的先生
Indeed, sir.
近距离射杀
Point blank range.
莫里亚蒂
Moriarty.
莫里亚蒂教授
Professor Moriarty.
好孩子
There's a good boy!
没事了
Everything's gonna be fine.
布莱克伍德的装置现在在哪
Where is Blackwood's device now?
特请处 先生
Secret Service have it, sir.
他们接管了这个案子
They've taken over the case.
我猜肯定少了一块部件
I bet there's a piece missing.
莫里亚蒂要的是装置的那一块
So Moriarty was after a piece of the machine.
而不是毒药
Not the poison.
这就显而易见
There's nothing more elusive than an obvious fact.
无线电部件才是装置的关键
The wire free invention was the goal all along.
艾德勒小姐只是转移我们的视线
And Addler was just the diversion.
他知道我会去追她
He knew I'd chase after her,
而装置就会无人看管
there by leaving the machine accessible.
无线电技术是一笔无穷的财富
The technology of that kind can be worth, an untold fortune.
想象一下 你可以通过电磁波远程控制任何机器
Imagine being able to control a radio device simply by sending a command via radio waves.
那就是未来 华生
It's the future, Watson.
我把最后一箱装上车了 先生
I've loaded the last of your boxes, sir.
- 好的 - 好的
- Well... - Well...
格莱斯顿
Gladston!
在它跑到门口前抓住它
Stop him before he gets to the front door.
克拉基
Clarky?
案件重开了
Case reopened.